Gina Lucy

Richmond, VA 23294

Phone: (757) 652-3703 | Email: ginalucy9@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/grlucy | GitHub: github.com/grlucy | Portfolio: www.ginalucy.com

SUMMARY

Web developer with a certificate in full stack web development from the University of Richmond. Background in marketing and graphic design with over 7 years of professional experience. A quick learner and collaborative problem-solver recognized for innovation and attention to detail. Positioned well to translate business goals into a cohesive online brand identity.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front End:

React, Redux, JavaScript, jQuery, Web APIs, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap, Materialize, Bulma, IndexedDB

Back End:

Node.js, Express, Handlebars, MongoDB, Mongoose, SQL, MySQL, Sequelize, Passport, Socket.io, REST APIs

Additional Skills:

Git, Agile Scrum & Kanban Methodology, Adobe XD, Technical Writing, Graphic and UI Design

PROJECTS

Dragon's Den Ecommerce | ecommerce.ginalucy.com | ecommerce-code.ginalucy.com

- A game store ecommerce website that enables online credit card/PayPal transactions with a store that can be searched, sorted, and filtered; a built-in inventory management system; and secure user authentication
- **Core responsibilities:** UI design; Back end development with Express, Node.js, and MongoDB; Shared responsibility for front end React, CSS/Bulma, and Braintree ecommerce development with team member
- **Technologies used:** MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js), Mongoose, Braintree, JavaScript, CSS, Bulma, HTML, Formspree API, Heroku, mLab, Dotenv

SQL To Do List | todo.ginalucy.com | todo-code.ginalucy.com

- A mobile-first, full-stack to do list app that enables users to add tasks, mark tasks complete, delete individual tasks, bulk delete, and track task completion progress
- Core responsibilities: Solo project; responsible for all design and development
- Technologies used: React, Redux, SQL, MySQL, Express, Node.js, Axios, JavaScript, Dotenv, CSS, HTML, Heroku, JawsDB

Friendango | friendango.ginalucy.com | friendango-code.ginalucy.com

- A social network for movie reviews that enables a user to submit their own reviews and view data about the reviews submitted either by all users or by only the users they follow
- Core responsibilities: UI design; HTML, CSS, Chart.js, and Handlebars development; Express routing and Sequelize queries for post routes; Heroku and JawsDB deployment
- **Technologies used:** Node.js, Express, Handlebars, MySQL, Sequelize, JavaScript, jQuery, Heroku, JawsDB, OMDB API, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Chart.js, ESLint, Dotenv, Passport

EXPERIENCE

Web Development Tutor (Self-Employed) | Richmond, VA

December 2019 - February 2020

Provided private tutoring to web development students in the areas of HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, and jQuery.

Gina Lucy

Richmond, VA 23294

Phone: (757) 652-3703 | Email: ginalucy9@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/grlucy | GitHub: github.com/grlucy | Portfolio: www.ginalucy.com

CBRE | Baltimore, MD

Senior Communications Specialist

Communications Specialist

Client Services Coordinator

April 2019 – October 2019

April 2017 – March 2019

July 2016 – March 2017

Served as Marketing Lead for business acquisition and disposition of multifamily commercial real estate properties with a cumulative sale value of over \$1.65 billion. Developed tailored marketing strategies and collateral. Designed and developed property marketing websites (HTML & CSS). Wrote marketing content. Designed graphics and page layouts for marketing collateral using Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, and InDesign. Collaborated with Sales Leads to develop time management, stakeholder relationship management, and file organization best practices.

CBRE | Hampton Roads | Norfolk, VA

Marketing Assistant

August 2015 - May 2016

Served as Marketing Lead for business acquisition and disposition of retail, office, and industrial commercial real estate properties. Led photography and photo editing training sessions for colleagues. Coordinated signage vendors. Served on a committee that developed a customized CRM database using the Apto/Salesforce platform. Recognized as CBRE | Hampton Roads Employee of the Quarter for Q3 2015.

McCallum Testing Laboratories | Chesapeake, VA

Contractor (Freelance)

September 2015 - February 2016

Developed new corporate website using HTML, CSS, and WordPress. Trained employees to handle routine site maintenance. Photographed employee headshots. Designed new corporate logo.

Virginia Beach Community Development Corporation | Virginia Beach, VA

Leader, Marketing and Community Relations

October 2014 – June 2015

Community Development Administrator

March 2014 - October 2014

Designed, maintained, and developed content for the corporate website and blog. Developed the five-year corporate strategic marketing and communications plan. Managed corporate stakeholder relations. Developed and supervised the marketing intern and volunteer program. Developed and trained staff in corporate brand standards. Designed graphics and wrote content for marketing collateral.

Old Dominion University | Norfolk, VA

PR & Marketing Specialist

April 2011 – October 2013

Served as project manager for the Office of Finance's major marketing initiatives. Handled website maintenance (HTML & CSS) for MABUG and the university tennis center. Developed, advertised, and taught the Monarch Millionaire free student financial literacy program, which served over 300 students. Developed electronic W-2 and eRefund promotions that achieved over 7,000 student sign-ups in one semester and saved the Office of Finance over \$40,000 in mailing costs. Served as Assistant Director of the Mid-Atlantic Banner User Group (MABUG) 2013 Conference, a three-day event with over 450 attendees.

EDUCATION

University of Richmond | Certificate, Full Stack Web Development (MERN Stack) October 2019 – April 2020 Recipient of the Golden Duck Award for "Most Likely to Become the Debugging King or Queen"

Old Dominion University | Bachelor of Science, Business Administration

January 2010 - May 2012

Major: Marketing; GPA: 4.00